{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is effect of decreasing membrane resistance on flux?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
        "c": "Constant",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some methods to increase flux through the membrane?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Backwashing of membrane",
        "b": "Stirring in the feed compartment",
        "c": "Increasing bulk concentration",
        "d": "Both a and b"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The effect of concentration polarisation is least important in which of the following processes?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Gas separation",
        "b": "Haemodialysis",
        "c": "Reverse Osmosis",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the explaination for your choice of answer in Q13 above?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Diffusivity is low in gas phase",
        "b": "Concentration boundary will not form",
        "c": "Diffusivity is very high in gas phase",
        "d": "Both b and c"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "If polarisation modulus in a Reverse Osmosis module is unity, the feed side mass transfer coefficient of the solute is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Very large",
        "b": "Very small",
        "c": "Is equal to the diffusinal resistance of the membrane",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "If reflection coefficient sigma is zero, an osmotic membrane is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Fully permeable",
        "b": "Impermeable",
        "c": "Partially permeable to the solute",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the selectivity of separation change with the increasing membrane thickness?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
        "c": "Remains unchanged",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In membrane filtration, the solute molecules are carried to the membrane surface by",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Knudsen diffusion",
        "b": "Fickian diffusion",
        "c": "Convection",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "How are the rejected solute molecules carried from membrane surface to the bulk?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Convection",
        "b": "Diffusive transport",
        "c": "Knudsen diffusion",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "With increased concentration polarisation on a Reverse Osmosis membrane at a constant applied pressure difference, the solvent flux decreases. What happens to the solute flux?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
        "c": "Remains unchanged",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
